

# Mrs Manminder Hewey Accredited Cognitive Behavioural Therapist & Trained EMDR Practitioner.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: <a href="mailto:info@healthcity.org.uk">info@healthcity.org.uk</a>,

Manminder.Hewey@healthcity.org.uk https:/healthcity.org.uk

### **Profile**

Over twenty years' experience working in primary and secondary care Mental Health setting within the NHS. I have acquired sound and proficient knowledge in providing evidence-based CBT, to include the third wave of interventions and EMDR. As an established and accredited CBT clinician, I bring advanced up to date knowledge and understand the importance in nurturing and developing staff. Therefore, I provide excellent quality CBT and clinical supervision for complex mental health presentations. I have a depth of knowledge in designing and facilitating group interventions. As a senior clinician also acquiring experience in providing line management, duty, and risk support for a large team, to further strengthen my leadership capabilities. Most importantly I build strong therapeutic alliances in a non-judgemental way to the clients I treat, resulting in positive outcomes.

### **Professional Registration**

- BABCP full accreditation: 090280
- EMDR 3-part training with EMDR Europe

#### **Skills**

- Trained and qualified in providing evidence-based:
  - -EMDR for trauma/PTSD.
- Trained and qualified in providing evidence-based CBT treatment for a spectrum of disorders including:
- Depression
- Low self-esteem
- Obsessive Compulsive Disorder
- Personality Disorders
- Bi-polar
- Complex-Post Traumatic Stress Disorder
- Generalised Anxiety
- Post traumatic stress disorder
- Social to Specific phobias
- Schizophrenia
- Paranoid Personality

### Qualifications

2008 – 2009: Post Graduate Diploma in Cognitive Behavioural Therapy, Royal Holloway University, UK.

#### **Employment History**

2023 – Present Senior CBT/EMDR Qualified Psychotherapist, Mental health integrated network Teams (M.I.N.T), West London NHS Trust, UK.

- Formulating complex treatment plans and assessments for my clients.
- Responsible for providing CBT clinical supervision to trainee therapists.
- Managing and facilitating the PTSD stabilisation group.

- Responsible for making clinical decisions around managing risk to provide support to junior staff members.
- Actively participating in daily multi-disciplinary team triage meetings to assess suitability of clients into the service.
- Weekly zoning meetings to monitor progress of complex individuals to include patients with Community Treatment Orders, increased risk of suicide or relapse and detainment under the mental health act.
- Attending weekly interface meetings with external agencies to ensure client care is optimised.
- Actively participate in reflective practice and ensure the wellbeing of my work colleagues.
- ❖ Initiating daily contact across the Multi-Disciplinary Team I work with.
- Charing weekly clinical case discussions for complex individuals.
- ❖ Facilitating weekly psychology clinical consultations to the team for psychology guidance and input.
- ❖ Attending monthly business meetings to help inform and guide service provision.
- Attending weekly / monthly clinical supervision for CBT and EMDR to enhance my clinical skills.

## 2018 – 2023: Senior Manager & CBT/EMDR Qualified Psychotherapist, I.A.P.T, West London NHS Trust, UK.

- Provided daily CBT and EMDR interventions to clients.
- Treated clients daily utilising CBT and EMDR interventions.
- ❖ Facilitated monthly line management of staff.
- Held Weekly CBT clinical supervision of multiple CBT staff members.
- Provided high level of senior duty cover for a large team.
- Responsible for monitoring staff sickness, maternity leave, annual leave, and conduct/capability issues with staff
- ❖ Actively involved in investigating complaints and serious incidents
- Participated in monthly clinical improvement meetings.
- Involved in weekly seniors' meetings to help improve service provision.
- Responsible for implementing a service user forum to help improve mental health services from a service user perspective.
- ❖ Involved in the implementation of better mental health access for 18- to 25-year-olds.
- Involved in helping to implement a new mental health integrated network team (MINT) across the borough.

### 2007 – 2018: CBT Psychotherapist, I.A.P.T, West London NHS Trust, UK.

- Provided CBT for clients presenting with mental health anxiety disorders.
- Treated clients using EMDR for complex PTSD presentations.
- Responsible for providing CBT clinical supervision for trainees.
- Actively involved in community events in providing mental health support.
- Provided community workshops as well as facilitated group interventions to hard-to-reach BAME individuals.

# 2007 – 2008: Graduate Mental Health Worker, NHS Mental Health & Wellbeing Service, West London NHS Trust, UK.

- Treated clients with mild to moderate anxiety disorders.
- Implemented appropriate and efficient IT systems.
- Promoted Mental Health Services to the BAME community to generate awareness.
- Attended monthly GP meetings as a link worker.

### **Training**

- - EMDR 3-part training with EMDR Europe
- Compassion Focused Therapy
- Dialectical Behavioural Therapy
- Medically Unexplained Symptoms
- Suicide Prevention and Risk management
- Mindful Based Cognitive Behavioural Therapy
- Deep Brain Re-Orienteering
- Treating Personality Disorders
- Long Term Conditions

### **Notable Achievements**

- ❖ Appearance on local radio station to promote mental health access.
- ❖ Multiple appearances on Zee TV for live phone-in questions regarding mental health.
- Front page coverage for an Interview with the West London Communication magazine.
- Involved in writing an article regarding hearing the voices of Graduate Mental Health worker experiences, published in the journal of psychiatry.
- Successfully completing a BAME leadership programme to support promotion from this minority into senior positions.

### <u>Interests</u>

Due to my natural curiosity and intertest in mental Health, I spend much of my free time reading and keeping abreast with the latest developments in mental health disorders. I have a particular interest in neuroscience and the development of the brain, so spend much of my time in reading around the subject. As a firm believer to good mental health, I feel it is imperative to have a healthy balance between work, rest and play. Therefore, outside of work I spend time socialising with likeminded individuals, enjoy walking and having a healthy routine and sleep schedule. Amongst my other interests, they include cooking, swimming, going on holidays and watching crime dramas.